University of Texas at Austin, School of Architecture, Student Work:
The University of Texas at Austin. University of Texas Libraries. Alexander Architectural Archives.
University of Texas at Austin, School of Architecture Student Work Drawings, Selected design studies produced by the students.
1915-2001
University of Texas at Austin. School of Architecture.
Accession number (s): see Archives staff
45 + drawings (as of 2001)
Alexander Architectural Archives, University of Texas Libraries, The University of Texas at Austin.
The School of Architecture Student Work collection includes a selection of coursework produced by University of Texas Architecture students in design studios from 1915 to the present. The projects include drawings of buildings, objects and human figures.
Scope and Content of the collection
The School of Architecture Student Work collection consists primarily of course work produced throughout the years by students in design studios of the School of Architecture. For course work that is documentary or for historic research (Measured Drawings or Historic Documentation class) see the University of Texas at Austin, School of Architecture, Texas Architecture Archive collection.
Other Finding Aids
Unpublished inventory in Archive.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the University of Texas Online Catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Subjects:
Buildings--Designs and plans.; Beaux-Arts buildings.
Document type:
Architectural drawings.; Renderings.; Student drawings.; Student works.; Watercolor drawings.
Restrictions on Access
This collection is open for research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using archival materials. As all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site, advance notice of at least three working days is required for retrieval. Certain items may require additional time for flattening or humidifying before they can be viewed. Access is by appointment only. Please contact the archives’ reference staff for further information.
Related Material
Seventeen photographs of UT Architecture student drawings are part of the University of Texas Campus-Old Main Building Collection (Discrete Collection 66) in the Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center Photography Collection at the University of Texas at Austin.
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Drawings Series
  Series Abstract
  Entries are indexed chronologically by the date listed on the drawings. Dates are offered if they can be derived from the drawings or gathered from other authoritative sources. Many drawings are not dated. This collection spans from 1915 - current. The collection is continuously added to and is not completely processed. For more information, please contact Archives staff.
  Entries without dates are sorted by Project Name and listed before those that provide dates. Project names are supplied by the cataloger, as title blocks on the drawings prove to be inconsistent and many drawings are not labeled. If available, the student's name and class information are provided in the Notes field.
  The term "drawing" includes both original works (such as pencil on trace paper, or ink on tracing clothe) as well as copies (such as sepia prints, blue line prints, etc.).
  - Dishes., Notes: Drawing by Craig Allen
  - Dome of Florence Cathedral., Notes: Drawing by Richard Dolros. Architect in 15th century was Fillipo Brunelleschi.
  - Figure drawing - Male., Notes: Drawing by Wolf Jessen, 19[?] September 28.
  - Figure Drawing - male., Notes: Drawing by J.H. Fisher
  - Figure Drawings., Notes: Drawing by Leslie McKay
  - Foot Bridge. First Analytique., Notes: Drawing by Charles M. Morton - UT, class B
  - Fruit Dish., Notes: Drawing by J. Ewing
  - Kitchen objects., Notes: Drawing by Talley
  - Kitchen objects., Notes: Drawing by Bob Quenselnut
  - School Chapel., Notes: Drawing by Charles Morton - UT, 2nd year design
  - Tea Kettle., Notes: Drawing by J. Scoggins, 19[?] November 26.
  - Vases and Bowls., Notes: Drawing by Carrotti?
  - Vases, Dishes., Notes: Drawing by Linden
  - Vases, Pots., Notes: Drawing by Liz Leasure
  - Classical Orders., 1915; Notes: Drawing by W.G.W., 1915 September.
  - Air transport terminal., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Class A V project. 38 × 61-3/4.
  - Architectural Terra Cotta Plant., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Class A II project mention. 29-1/2 × 40"
  - Grand Stair Hall with elevation mural., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. 2nd mention. 29-1/8 × 40-1/2"
  - Greek temple., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Class AII archeology. 37-1/2 × 58-1/2.
  - Marine Museum (oceanside acquarium)., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Class B III Project that received the Honorable Mention for the Beaux-Arts competition. 37-1/2 × 27"
  - Outdoor fountain and plaza., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Mention 3.23 × 29".
  - Seaside recreation center., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Class A Minor project, 2nd Medal. 40-1/2 × 29-1/16"
  - Spanish facade., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Mention 3? 23 × 29".
  - Suburban residence., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Submitted by Decorator. 26-3/4 × 38-1/2".
  - Town hall., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. Class BII project. 27-1/8 × 37-1/4"
  - Waterworks and grounds with collossal guardian beasts., 1929-1933; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. 40 × 58-3/4"
  - Refreshment stand., 1931; Notes: Drawing by Paul E. Pressler. Pressler attended school between 1929-1933. A minor project. 37×28".
  - Recreation Center on an Island., 1932; Notes: Drawing by Nancy M. TacQuand, 4th year design, 1932 April 29
  - Orphanage., 1937; Notes: Drawing by Douglas Yater, 5th year design, 1937 November.
  - Reflection., 1937; Notes: Drawing by W. Callister
  - Figure Drawing - Male, Female Statues., 1938; Notes: Drawing by Ed Reichert, 1938 November 8.
  - Small Residence., 1938; Notes: Drawing by Douglas L. Yater, 1938 September.
  - Flower in a Vase., 1939; Notes: Drawing by Bill Pickle
  - Municipal Air Terminal for Austin, Texas, 1939; Notes: Drawing by Joseph W. Baxter, 5th year, 1939 May 19.2 renderings and 3 sheets of specs.
  - Restaurant with Outside Counter Service., 1939; Notes: Drawing by Edward Reichter, 4th year design
  - State Capitol Building for Texas., 1940; Notes: Drawing by W. R. Lane Jr., 5th year design, 1940 May 21.
  - Memorial Hall., 1942; Notes: Drawing by Ned A Cole
  - Retirement Center for the Future., 1942; Notes: Drawing by Mims Jackson, 5th year, 1942 December.
  - Zoological Garden, Aviary., 1946; Notes: Drawing by Joseph R. Coleman, ARC 526, 1946 July 24
  - Dishes., 1947; Notes: Drawing by Meredith, 1947 February 2
  - Dormitory for a Prep School in a Small Texas Village., 1947; Notes: Drawing by Joe T. Pursell, 1947 July 30
  - Kettles, Vases., 1947; Notes: Drawing by K.D. Vinson Jr.
  - Vases, Dishes., 1948; Notes: Drawing by John R. Mayner Jr., 1948 March 16
  - Apartments in Arrid Climate Thesis?, 1950; Notes: Drawing by John P. Work, ARC564, 1950 Spring
  - Public Schools in Northeast Texas., 1950; Notes: Drawing by Harold Box